The next day was foggy. Everything on the farm was dripping wet. The grass
looked like a magic carpet. The asparagus patch looked like a silver forest.
On foggy mornings, Charlotte's web was truly a thing of beauty.
This morning, each thin strand was decorated with dozens of tiny beads of
water. The web glistened in the light and made a pattern of loveliness and
mystery like a delicate veil. Even Lurvy, who wasn't particularly
interested in beauty, noticed the web when he came with the pig's breakfast.
He noted how clearly it showed up, and he noted how big and carefully built it
was. And then he took another look, and he saw something that made him set his
pale down. There in the center of the web, neatly woven in block letters, was
a message. It said, "Some pig."
Lurvy felt weak. He brushed his hand across his eyes and stared harder at
Charlotte's Web. "I'm saying things," he whispered. He dropped to his knees and
uttered a short prayer. Then forgetting all about Wilbur's breakfast, he walked
back to the house and called Mr.
Zuckerman. I think you'd better come down to the pig pan, he said.
What's the trouble? asked Mr. Zuckerman.
Anything wrong with the pig?
Not exactly, said Lurvy. Come and see for yourself.
The two men walked silently down to Wilbur's yard. Lurvy pointed to the
spider's web. "Do you see what I see?"
he asked. Zuckerman stared at the writing on the web. Then he murmured the words, "Some pig."
Then he looked at Lurvy. Then they both began to tremble.
Charlotte, sleepy after her night's exertions, smiled as she watched. Wilbur
came and stood directly under the web.
"Some pig!" muttered Lurvy in a low voice. "Some pig!" whispered Mr.
Zuckerman. They stared and stared for a long time at Wilbur. Then they stared at Charlotte.
"You don't suppose that that spider?"
began Mr. Zuckerman, but he shook his head and didn't finish the sentence.
Instead, he walked solemnly back up to the house and spoke to his wife. "Edith,
something has happened," he said in a weak voice. He went into the living room
and sat down, and Mrs. Zuckerman followed.
"I've got something to tell you, Edith," he said. "You better sit down." Mrs.
Zuckerman sank into a chair. She looked pale and frightened. "Edith," he said,
trying to keep his voice steady. "I think you had best be told that uh we
have a very unusual pig." A look of complete bewilderment came over Mrs.
Zuckerman's face. "Homer Zuckerman, what in the world are you talking about?" she said.
This is a very serious thing, Edith," he replied. "Our pig is completely out of
the ordinary." "What's unusual about the pig?" asked Mrs. Zuckerman, who was
beginning to recover from her scare.
"Well, I don't really know yet," said Mr. Zuckerman. "But we have received a
sign, Edith. A mysterious sign. A miracle has happened on this farm.
There was a large spider's web in the doorway of the barn cellar, right over
the pig pin. And when Larvy went to feed the pig this morning, he noticed the web
cuz it was foggy. And you know how a spider's web looks very distinct in a
fog. And right spang in the middle of the web, there were the words some pig.
The words were woven right into the web.
They were actually part of the web, Edith. I know because I have been down
there and seen them. It says, "Some pig just as clear as clear can be. There can
be no mistake about it. A miracle has happened and a sign has occurred here on
Earth right on our farm, and we have no ordinary pig." "Well," said Mrs.
Zuckerman, it seems to me you're a little off. It seems to me we have no ordinary spider.
Oh no, said Zuckerman. It's the pig that's unusual. It says so right there
in the middle of the web. Maybe so, said Mrs. Zuckerman. Just the same, I intend
to have a look at that spider. It's just a common gray spider, said Zuckerman.
They got up and together they walked down to Wilbur's yard. You see, Edith,
it's just a common gray spatter.
Wilbur was pleased to receive so much attention. Lurvy was still standing
there, and Mr. and Mrs. Zuckerman, all three, stood for about an hour reading
the words on the web over and over and watching Wilbur.
Charlotte was delighted with the way her trick was working. She sat without
moving a muscle and listened to the conversation of the people.
When a small fly blundered into the web just beyond the word pig, Charlotte
dropped quickly down, rolled the fly up, and carried it out of the way. After a
while, the fog lifted, the web dried off, and the words didn't show up so
plainly. The Zuckerman's and Lurvy walked back to the house. Just before
they left the pig pin, Mr. Zuckerman took one last look at Wilbur.
You know, he said in an important voice.
I've thought all along that that pig of ours was an extra good one. He's a solid
pig. That pig is as solid as they come.
You notice how solid he is around the shoulders, Lurvy? Sure, sure I do, said
Lurvy. I've always noticed that pig.
He's quite a pig. He's long and he's smooth, said Zuckerman.
That's right, agreed Lurvy. He's as smooth as they come. He's some pig.
When Mr. Zuckerman got back to the house. He took off his workclo and put
on his best suit. Then he got into his car and drove to the minister's house.
He stayed for an hour and explained to the minister that a miracle had happened
on the farm. So far, said Zuckerman, only four people on earth know about
this miracle. Myself, my wife, Edith, my hired man, Lurvy, and you.
Don't tell anybody else, said the minister. We don't know what it means
yet, but uh perhaps if I give thought to it, I can explain it in my sermon next
Sunday. There can be no doubt that you have a most unusual pig. I intend to
speak about it in my sermon and point out the fact that this community has
been visited with a wondrous animal.
By the way, does this pig have a name?
Why yes, said Mr. Zuckerman. My little niece calls him Wilbur. She's a rather
queer child, full of notions. She raised the pig on a bottle, and I bought him
from her when he was a month old. He shook hands with the minister and left.
Secrets are hard to keep. Long before Sunday came, the news spread all over the county.
Everybody knew that a sign had appeared in a spider's web on the Zuckerman
place. Everybody knew that the Zuckermanman's had a wondrous pig.
People came from miles around to look at Wilbur and to read the words on
Charlotte's Web. The Zuckerman's driveway was full of cars and trucks from morning till night.
Fords and Chevys and Buick Roadmasters and GMC pickups and Plymouths and
Studebakers and Packards and Doodtos with gyroatic transmissions and
osmobiles with rocket engines and Jeep station wagons and Pontiacs.
The news of the wonderful pig spread clear up into the hills, and farmers
came rattling down in buggies and buck boards to stand hour after hour at
Wilbur's pin, admiring the miraculous animal. All said they had never seen
such a pig before in their lives.
When Fern told her mother that Avery had tried to hit the Zuckerman spider with a
stick, Mrs. Arable was so shocked that she sent Avery to bed without any supper
as punishment. In the days that followed, Mr. Zuckerman was so busy
entertaining visitors that he neglected his farmwork. He wore his good clothes
all the time now, got right into them when he got up in the morning.
Mrs. Zuckerman prepared special meals for Wilbur. Lurvy shaved and got a
haircut, and his principal farm duty was to feed the pig while people looked on.
Mr. Zuckerman ordered Lurvy to increase Wilbur's feedings from three meals a day
to four meals a day. The Zuckermanmans were so busy with visitors, they forgot
about other things on the farm. The blackberries got ripe, and Mrs.
Zuckerman failed to put up any blackberry jam. The corn needed hoing
and Lurvy didn't find time to hoe it.
On Sunday, the church was full. The minister explained the miracle. He said
that the words on the spider's web proved that human beings must always be
on the watch for the coming of wonders.
All in all, the Zuckermanman's pig pin was the center of attraction. Fern was
happy, for she felt that Charlotte's trick was working and that Wilbur's life
would be saved. But she found that the barn was not nearly as pleasant. Too
many people. She liked it better when she could be all alone with her friends, the animals.
Chapter 12. A meeting.